Good morning to all residents of Niigata Prefecture on Sunday!
Gatatube
I know some of you are watching this for the first time.
I'm Kondo Honmoto, Niigata Prefecture's smooth comedian with 230,000 YouTube subscribers.
I'm Kondo Motomoto, a Niigata Prefecture smooth comedian with 230,000 YouTube subscribers.
I'm Mona Sugiyama, NST announcer.
Gattatube has moved to a new location on Sunday at this time.
We've moved!
Now, let me introduce our first guest for the new year!
Good morning, the morning chime has sounded, and it's us, the students of Ebisu Junior High School.
We are Ebisu Chugaku.
We are Ebisu Chugaku, number 3, Rika Maeyama...
Attendance number 16.
Ha-ha-ha-ha...
Good morning, the morning chime has rung.
We are Ebisu Chugaku.
We are Ebisu Chugaku students number 3, Maeyama Rika and
Sakurayama, number 16.
Nice to meet you.
It's our first time here, so it's nice to meet you.
If you're Ebichu, that means you're both junior high school students, right?
Yes, I'm in the third year of junior high school.
That's right.
Maematsu-san.
You're still in junior high.
It's already April.
Ha-ha-ha!
Scary, scary.
I was in junior high school at the time of filming. I mean, I'm average.
Yes, I'm in junior high school.
Like that.
How about you, Mr. Mae-Matsu?
I'm in middle school.
No, no, no...
I'm sorry.
Sorry. - PP?
I'm in 15th grade.
Ha-ha-ha-ha.
Let's take a look at the first video with these two students from Ebichu!
First, we asked Niigata high school students what they are good at and what they are proud of!
Now, let's all pretend to be in the VTR!
Seino
Gattatube
Tell us about your special skills and boasts. We asked them about their special skills and boasts in front of Niigata Station.
I'm sorry to interrupt, but there's a program on NHK Niigata General TV called "Gattatube".
Do you know it? I was on it a little while ago.
I'm a friend of yours from the broadcasting contest.
I see.
I appeared in this corner with a girl who competed in a national broadcasting contest.
Two, one, go ahead.
One day... the Buddha was strolling along the Paradise Bridge.
He came out of nowhere. Do you have any special skills?
Kirie.
She's in the art club at her high school.
It's more detailed than I thought.
That's amazing... you cut all that out.
She cuts with a design knife and paints on the back.
Do you show your work in exhibitions?
I don't really exhibit my work.
I give them as gifts to my friends.
I received a bookmark as a gift.
She is not the type of person who likes to give handmade gifts.
For example, can I have her make one for Gatatube?
Like a gutter tube robot?
A robot, yes.
The finished product is in the studio.
Here is the work that the high school girl made for us.
It's the new logo of Gattatube.
Thank you very much.
If you look closely, you can see that the letters in the word "gata" are really detailed.
It's amazing!
It's a paper cutout!
Amazing!
My head doesn't hurt.
It doesn't hurt my head.
Look closer.
How many hours did it take you to make this?
It took you two days to make it.
I was in the art club in junior high school.
But I've never done art like this.
What did you do in art club?
I did chores for the teacher.
I put up posters around the school.
I didn't do any art at all.
I'm moving this Sunday.
Gattatube, a video presentation program in Niigata and other places.
Guests were Rika Mayama and Megumi Sakurai from the popular idol group
Rika Mayama and Ema Sakurai of the popular idol group Shiritsu Ebisu Chugaku
How many times have you been to Niigata?
About 10 times.
Is it a place with which you have a deep connection?
Yes, I look forward to eating koftoyaki every time I come.
Are you going to eat it again today?
I want to eat it today too!
I'm urging you to eat it through the screen.
Please bring it to the staff.
Mr. Sakurai, have you been here several times?
This is my first time in Niigata.
How do you feel now that you're here?
I was just talking with Mr. Kazutani.
The air is so clean.
I thought it was different from the air in Tokyo.
I wonder what the air is like in Tokyo.
It has less oxygen than here.
I think it's the same.
Where do you think of when you think of sightseeing spots in Niigata?
I bought strawberries at Furusato Village.
What kind of strawberries are they?
Echigohime...
Here she is, Echigohime!
So, for those of you who are not from Niigata Prefecture...
Where do people from outside of Niigata Prefecture go to for sightseeing?
I've done a survey to see where people from outside of Niigata Prefecture go to for sightseeing.
Please take a look at this VTR!
Seino
Gatatube
NST Niigata General TV
To all of you who have come from outside of the prefecture
Where do you go to see the sights in Niigata?
I asked them.
A colleague and his wife.
I see.
I used to live in Niigata.
I've been transferred from one place to another, and I've been going around in circles.
I'm retired now, so I'm staying with the people who took care of me.
A couple from Yokohama and their work colleague.
The food is good!
First of all, the food!
Teradome is the place to be!
Teradome is delicious!
You can buy good food there!
Niigata is famous for seafood from the Sea of Japan!
Teradome Fish Market Street is very popular.
Yashiko for hot springs and mountain streams
Yahiko is also a staple of Niigata sightseeing!
There are plenty of shrines, hot springs, and leisure activities!
What was my favorite river in Niigata?
What river was it?
Cherry blossoms along the Shinano River
My father used to live in Niigata
He said he could never forget the cherry blossoms at Yasuragi-tei.
When spring came that year in Niigata...
He really loved it.
He said spring has finally come.
This is Niigata's TV station.
Next is a woman who comes to Niigata once a month for work.
She comes to Niigata once a month on business.
She works with breast cancer patients.
and wigs for anti-cancer drugs.
I visit hospitals.
There are many hospitals that are not open right now.Many hospitals can't get in right now.
So you can rent a space.
I'm thinking of renting a space, gathering patients and pitching in.
I don't know about tourist attractions.
I haven't looked into it.
He's too busy with work to go sightseeing.
I'm sure he's going home after a long day of drinking.
I'm sure the sake here tastes better.
Prime Minister Abe and Mr. Takachiyo...
I'm looking forward to finding my favorite destinations in the short time I have before the bullet train back home!
Prime Minister Abe in Hashimoto and Prime Minister Takachiyo in Minami-Unonuma are his favorites.
I'm on a business trip. I come here once a month.
This father also comes to Niigata once a month on business.
Well, I've been here on a private visit. It was nice in Niigata in May.
I rented a car and drove all over. I drove to Nagaoka and Tatsuno.
I heard that driving in Niigata in May is the best because of the high power outage rate.
I would like to visit places like Ishikawa Uncho when I have more time in the future.
What I am interested in now is visiting the works of Uncho Ishikawa, who is also called the Michelangelo of Japan.
Next is a mother from Yamagata.
Marinepia Nihonkai in Niigata City, which is well known even among people outside the prefecture.
When my kids were little, we used to drive from Yamagata and it takes less than 4 hours to get there.
Four hours is quite a long drive!
At a company training session.
This is also an older brother from Yamagata.
Ramen restaurant in Kameda
Yamagata residents are also impressed by Niigata's ramen shop.
You mean Niigata City and Yamagata City had more than two ramen products?
Oh yes, they are totally different!
But it was delicious. I really liked it.
Yamagata's ramen is very light.
This one is thicker.
It's very rich.
What about your favorite sightseeing spots?
I've been to Niigata many times on business, but I don't know any tourist attractions.
There are many people who come to Niigata on business many times but don't know of any tourist attractions.
I can see why they tend to go for ramen.
It's the food, isn't it?
Is there anything you would recommend? Do you have any recommendations?
I'm from Kashiwazaki, so I go to the market.
There is a fish called "Nodoguro" (throat blackfish), which is a very expensive fish.
Do you know what it is? It's called Nodoguro because it has a black throat.
The person who eats it also has a black throat.
I didn't know that.
I'm lying when I say I didn't know that.
It's very white meat, isn't it?
What's wrong with you today?
I want to enjoy the reaction of "What's wrong with you today?
No, no, no!
How do young women see Niigata?
Many of the women walking the streets are very elegant.
Thank you very much.
Also, Mr. Negikko told me that
I hear that many of the fans in Niigata are a bit reserved.
But instead, they have a lot of passion that they keep at home.
He told me that.
It's true that at first glance, I'm a little nervous about whether they are excited or not.
But every time we come to Niigata, I have the impression that there are always a lot of visitors.
There are many things that Niigata Prefecture has to offer its residents.
I think we want people to come to Niigata for sightseeing.
Please visit us, and we look forward to seeing you!
After this, we will investigate what kind of souvenirs out-of-prefecture people buy in Niigata.
And what are some Niigata specialties that are praised by the shrimp Chinese drum board?
Before that
Let's go to a high school in Niigata!
Here we go!
Let's go to Niigata High School!
Let's go to a high school in Niigata!
This time, let's go to Niigata Horse Racing Academy High School!
You know what they say about Christianity.
Yes, that's right.
Wait a minute.
Is this in the school?
A pipe organ?
That's what it is, isn't it?
They have an organ.
That's amazing.
We'll be praying for you at graduation.
Oh, my... you've all been through so much.
You all have such beautiful hearts.
It was kind of, you know, nice...
It was wonderful.
I'm Sakura Ito, student council president of the Koko High School class.
I am Kawakami from Shizuoka class, the chairperson of the 2nd year executive committee.
I am a member of the committee to send off the 1st year students for the annual meeting.
I am Mao Yamazaki, a member of the 1st year class.
The first-year students are very grateful to the third-year students for making them smile so much, and they also want to make their own smiles on their last day.
We also want to make them smile on the last day of the school year by ourselves.
We are trying to make them smile a lot.
Lovely!
The seniors are having fun too!
Crying
The goal of the second year students was to create something together.
We made art.
We made the word "thank you".
and then each sophomore wrote a thank-you note to the third grader.
and made it into a piece of art.
The design is beautiful.
It's true.
I was a part of the ceremony.
I was really moved to see so many people giving their all to the chorus.
I think we were able to create something very powerful and wonderful.
Hallelujah, you know.
I remember singing "Hallelujah".
I think about it.
Celebrating each other's graduation.
And...
I wonder if it was my life at Honda School.
Some of us saw each other for the first time at today's graduation ceremony.
I think my life was tied to a mask.
I think the good thing about competition is that you love people like yourself.
I think that's the good thing about competition.
Friends and colleagues support each other.
The teachers greet students in a gentlemanly manner.
and teachers greet students in a gentlemanly manner.
From our point of view, we were greatly affected by the coronavirus.
It was a school year that was greatly affected by the coronavirus from our point of view.
We had to find out what we could do and how we could do it in the face of the coronavirus, and we worked very hard on that.
They searched for what they could do and worked hard at it.
I really admire these seniors.
Thank you very much.
We're really fired up.
The ceremony with all our might
We've prepared so much for this event, so when we saw the expressions on the faces of the third-year students
When I saw the expressions on the faces of the third-year students when they made their presentations
I felt that all the hard work we've put in up to this point has paid off and we're done.
I wish you all the best on your new stage.
Congratulations!
That's all for now, K-1 performance controllers!
Oh, no.
I could tell from your expressions that you had a fulfilling school life.
You must have had a wonderful school life.
Let's Go to High School in Niigata is looking for schools that would like to be interviewed!
Please let us visit you!
We will continue to tell you about the interesting rumors in Niigata, but for now, here is a short video clip of Niigata!
This week, we're going to show you the cherry blossoms in full bloom.
Thank you very much.
This is a video of cherry blossoms shot with a special technique by YouTuber Smallworks, a company employee who shoots the scenery of Niigata as a hobby!
Amazing.
It feels like CG!
Cherry blossoms are so beautiful.
It's the season.
I can see a lot of cherry blossoms.
You're wearing blue slats.
It's nice.Wonderful.
Good night.
I think it's a little sad.
No, it was beautiful.
It was edited to make it look like they were all blooming at once.
It was soothing.
How was it, Mr. Sakurai?
I was just thinking how different it is when there's no blooming.
It's true that the scenery becomes more gorgeous when they're in bloom, isn't it?
This time of year, I really want to listen to spring songs like cherry blossom songs.
I really want to listen to spring songs like cherry blossom songs.
Do you have any cherry blossom songs?
There is a song called "Sakura go-round" which is a cherry blossom song.
But it's not often sung live.
I see.
More often sung in Ebichu is a song called "Ume" (plum blossoms).
When people think of spring flowers, they tend to think of cherry blossoms.
But actually, plum blossoms bloom before cherry blossoms.
Plum blossoms are usually the third most popular flower in a chapter.
That's why the plum blossoms are often treated like a shadowy presence.
That's why we sing the song "Ume" with the intention of making it even more popular in Ebichu.
Can you tell us a little bit about the song?
Blossoming plum blossoms
Though not like the cherry blossoms
Enduring the weight of the snow
I sing of spring with the pride of having breathed it all out. Sing to me.
I'm sure I said it. It's as if I'd forgotten.
I'm sorry... for giving this to my senpai.
Who wrote the lyrics?
It's written by Daiin-jan, the famous Yada-in, the famous Yada-in, and in spring...
When spring comes, fans listen to this plum song.
I'm glad to hear that you're singing "Plum Blossom" in Ebichu
Now, the second topic of Niigata's interesting rumors is, what are you buying?
Now, the second theme of Niigata's most interesting rumors is what people are buying, and this time, Mr. Morimoto, please pretend to be on the VCR
Now let's go... Gatatube!
Thank you very much. Why did you get it?
What did you actually buy as a souvenir from Niigata?
This father's favorite is Kashiwae's Sake Chazuke.
This father's favorite is Kashiwae's sake chazuke.
There are so many to choose from. I can't give them away because I can't hold them all.
It's for your own enjoyment.
What did you just buy? Rice with soy sauce.
You don't know?
Sake.
Pado sake and soy sauce.
It's Niigata's version of sake.
And a lot of cute packaging.
This one is from my hometown near Nagaoka.
I'm from near Nagaoka, so only people from that area eat this.
It's delicious just the way it is!
Soy sauce okoshi is well-known in Nagaoka and other areas of Chuetsu.
It has recently become popular nationwide.
Salad fork
It's so good, go buy one!
A limited edition product only available in Niigata. Salad Hope by Kameda Seika.
Convenient souvenirs to bring back to your workplace!
Sasa-dango (bamboo grass dumplings)
Everyone likes them so much!
I'm so sorry I can only give you one at a time!
Sasa-dango are the king of Niigata souvenirs!
On the other hand, there is also a female opinion
There are people who can't see each other because of their biology.
If you don't give them something, you can't give it to someone else.
Sasa-dango, right?
It's a pain in the ass to deal with the peasants.
Some new forces are coming to buy those bamboo dumplings.
To buy the cute panda ones.
Is there a screening of the one with the bamboo grass dumplings in it somewhere?
I'll definitely buy these!
A popular product made by Passionate Kotake Seika, which wraps bamboo grass dumplings in bread dough.
It's become a hot topic on Instagram and other social media
It has become known even outside of the prefecture!
Amazake has been on the menu recently, and the most popular item is Mitaka's salted and pickled salmon.
Mitaka's salted salmon became popular by word of mouth among young comedians.
Even in heaven. Even as an accompaniment to rice.
Which of these products caught your attention, everyone in the shrimp club?
I was surprised at how delicious they all looked.
I tried the Salad Hope today before the show and it was delicious!
I was thinking about buying a whole bag of it today.
I'm going to tell the staff about it through the screen.
Mayama-san said he'd have a beer to go with it
Yes, that's right!
It's just like when you go on a road trip and after a live performance
After a live performance, you can have a beer and a beer in your hotel room
and eat it with a crunchy bite.
I also love salted salmon.
Have you ever had it?
Yes, I have. It's delicious.
You don't have any specials yet?
No, I don't.
The two members of Ebichu will check out popular souvenirs available at Niigata Station and other places.
We'll have two members of Ebichu check out some popular souvenirs available at Niigata Station and other places.
We're going to try the salted salmon.
I want to try it!
I want you to try it!
Ehehe!
Heh heh heh.
Ha-ha-ha-ha!
Why are you so cute?
You have a nice smile, even before you eat it.
Yeah, it's good.
Is it spicy?
It's a little spicy, but it's also sweet.
It's a new texture, a new experience.
Mochi Mochi?
Mochi-mochi?
The salmon is sticky.
The salmon is glutinous?
I've always wanted to hear "sticky".
I was wondering about the kinpira.
Do you know Tanakaya's kinpira dumplings?
I've never heard of them.
They're really good!
They are really delicious.
Bon appétit!
Yes.
It's big, isn't it?
Mochi Mochi
This one is stickier.
The real mochi... just like this one.
It goes well with something salty.
The senpai was playing with something in the back.
He was playing behind her.
He was talking hard.
What's the matter?
I just wanted to show you that I have this goldfish.
There is no need to be shaking.
There are so many things in Niigata.
It's hard to decide which one to choose.
It's hard to decide which one to choose, but I'm sure.
Please find your favorite one!
We're looking for Niigata rumors and local videos you'd like us to look into for the show on Catatubes!
Now, here's an announcement from Shiritsu Ebisu Chugaku!
Yes, Shiritsu Ebisu Chugaku and Spring Tour 2023 100% Ebisu Zum!
May 7 at Niigata Terrsa!
Wow! Please tell us about the highlights of this tour.
Yes, it's called "100% Ebisu Zum".
Ebichu has been performing live quite often.
I think this show will be filled with the charm of our live performances.
I'm sure that everyone in Niigata will be like this at first.
I'm sure everyone in Niigata will be excited to see what was going to happen at first.
What's that? I'm sure everyone in Niigata will be excited to see how it all turned out in the end.
I am sure that the people of Niigata will be excited by the 10 of us.
We are looking forward to seeing you.
Yes, you'll be smiling before you know it.
I'll be looking forward to seeing you in Ebichu.
We look forward to seeing you again next week on Gattatube!
Thank you very much.
Let's all go together for the last time.
Let's go, Gattatube!Seen it, gatatube!
Watch it!
Gattatube is available on Youtube on my favorite Nii Gattatube channel!